# **Melanie Hughson**

3917 Southwest Huber St.
Portland, OR 97219
Cell: 503.329.4042
Melanie.Hughson@gmail.com

### CAREER OBJECTIVE

To hit the ground running with a growing, dynamic organization that will provide new challenges and opportunities in project management, where I can bring the following experience:

- Effectively align team members around organizational strategies and values.
- Exceptional relationship building and communication skills with the dexterity to lead.
- Detail oriented planner with a history of exceeding expectations, minimizing risk and staying within budget.
- Examine the scope of a project both creatively and critically.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Owner / Property Manager

2004 - Present

Oregon Realty Advisors, Inc.

Portland, OR

- Manage all aspects of single-family residential properties including market analysis, negotiating lease terms, advertising and showing properties, processing applications, managing vendors, contractors and maintenance staff, collecting rents, preparing tenant notices as required and performing regular property inspections.
- Interview, hire, train, and motivate contract staff to ensure a smooth operation.
- Ensure compliance with Oregon Landlord Tenant Law, HOA rules and the Fair Housing Act.
- Drive advertising efforts and manage all areas of renting a short term vacation rental in Bend, OR including: providing high-level customer service to guests, preparing rental agreements, screening guests, processing payments, managing maintenance vendors and providing emergency on-call services.
- Coordinate and manage all office functions, timely answering calls, emails, maintaining property records and reports.

## **Executive Assistant to the President and CEO**

April 2005 - April 2006

OXIS International, Inc.

Portland, OR

- Key transitional player in company merger and shut down, maintained employee morale and provided HR support.
- Provided comprehensive, high-level support for the President & CEO through superior communication, interpersonal and organizational skills. Managed investor relations and distribution of press releases.
- Developed and maintained vendor databases, prepared expense reports, met regularly with accounts payable staff, and managed petty-cash accounts. Organized staff meetings and travel arrangements for President and Board.

## **Operations Coordinator**

February 2002 - August 2003

NIKE, Inc.

Beaverton, OR

- Identified communication inadequacies within and between NIKE corporate headquarters and retail stores, successfully developed high-level internal database and processes to reduce redundant communications.
- Key project management support role in New Store Opening Team including managing logistics, supply orders and coordinating travel.

#### **EDUCATION**

Portland State University Business & Economics September 2003 - June 2005 Portland Community College Associate of Science, September 2003